Andrew Crawford

St Paul, Minnesota 55104

Phone: (605) 691-4742 | Email: crawnicles@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/crawnicles/ | GitHub: https://github.com/crawnicles

Summary

Data analyst with an aptitude in python and drawing insights via data. 10+ years experience with collaboration across teams and independent work. Based in the twin cities with a BA Economics in 2018. Three years financial services experience in collateral management, SWIFT support, and financial advising. Completed the Fintech Coding Bootcamp offered through the University of Minnesota in March 2022 learning Python, Standard Query Language (SQL), and Amazon Web Services (AWS). Transitioning to data science to improve my information when making decisions. A curiosity of how computers work, programming and engineering converged towards a future in software development and data analysis. A company looking for a candidate driven towards providing data and software solutions would value these skills, projects, and experiences.

Technical Skills

Tools: Time-Series Analysis, Linear Regression, Logistic Regression, Classification, Jira, Visual Studio, Pycharm, IntelliJ

Libraries: Sklearn, tensorflow, keras, Scikit-learn

Languages: Python, Java, JavaScript, STATA, R, SQL, VBA, Node.js **Data Visualization:** Tableau, Plot.ly, Matplotlib, Seaborn, HTML, Streamlit

SQL: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, MS SQL

Python: Pandas, PyViz, NumPY, SciPy, SQLAlchemy, Jupyter Notebook, Spyder, Django

AWS: SageMaker

Excel: VBA, Macros, Pivot Tables/Charts, Index/Match, VLOOKUP

Projects

Predicting Fintech Bootcamp Salary | https://github.com/Crawnicles/Predicting-Salaries

- Using job descriptions and key skills, this model predicts the salary of a job given the skills required to perform the job.
- Responsibilities included Data Exploration, Data Preparation, and Data Cleanup. Using the Monster Application programming interface (API) we isolated jobs with relevant skills from class.
- Tools / languages used Python, Machine learning models

Book Recommendations | https://github.com/Crawnicles/Recommend_books

- Using goodreads data, a search tool finds the book id associated with a title to create a list of liked books
- The program compares your liked books to other users liked books and recommends their highly rated books
- Written in Python using pandas, numpy, sklearn, javascript, html

Algorithmic Trading Interface | https://github.com/Crawnicles/Algorithmic-Trading-App

- Created Larry Williams break-out volatility strategy and modified it to test the strategy in Crypto markets
- Written in Python and displayed through Streamlit

Experience

Society for Worldwide Interbank Financial Telecommunications (SWIFT) Support Sep 2021 – Feb 2022 St Paul, MN

Performed UAT testing and analysis of SWIFT messages in order to ensure accuracy and identify errors proactively and communicate with multiple teams utilizing SWIFT messaging.

Key Accomplishments:

- Reduced redundancy in data storage by utilizing VBA and a shared cloud storage
- Automated multiple day to day tasks by building macros and using rules in outlook

Capital Markets Analyst I Wells Fargo Jan 2019 – Mar 2021 Minneapolis, MN Managed incoming margin calls for derivative trading, managing 25+ systems/softwares daily, and solving client problems as they arise. Conducted dispute and break reconciliations, and prepare reports for consideration and presentation by senior management

Key Accomplishments:

- Implemented a three person pod structure to silo the tasks of one analyst into three roles margin calls, breaks, and disputes and tracked performance metrics
- Created training guide through powerpoint introducing new VBA, decision trees, flow charts, and step-by-step instructions

Education

Boot Camp Certificate: University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, MN

Sep 2021 – Mar 2022

• A six month program practicing technical programming skills in Python, JavaScript, SQL Databases, Tableau, Big Data, Blockchain, and Machine Learning

Bachelor of Arts Economics: University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, Minnesota

Minor in Spanish: Fundación Ortega y Gasset, Buenos Aires, Argentina

2014 – 2018

2016 – 2017